A Guide to the Governor James Barbour Executive Papers, 1812-1814
Library of Virginia
Abraham Douglas, and later William Campbell, Keeper of the Penitentiary, communicates with Governor Barbour regarding the conduct of certain prisoners during their confinement (1812 Jan. 14 & 28); the amount of commissions allowed him and his assistants on the profits of the Penitentiary (1812 Feb. 14); the pardon of John Moss by the President (1812 Feb. 20); the price of seine twine, cotton cloth, & other articles manufactured at the Penitentiary (1812 March 30); and a statement of the operations of the Penitentiary from 1 December 1811 to 13 May 1812 (1812 June 24). Douglas submitted his resignation on 30 March 1812 and was succeeded by William Campbell. Campbell writes regarding similar topics including the price of articles manufactured at the Penitentiary (1812 Nov. 6); a model of a miniature double field piece (1812 Nov. 16); rations allowed at the Penitentiary (1812 Nov. 28); extra services for superintending the powder magazine (1813 Jan. 21); the price of nails manufactured at the Penitentiary (1813 Feb. 22); a new privy for the Penitentiary (1813 March 7); the cases of Jeremiah B. Jackson & Dolly Chappell (1813 April 8); traveling expenses for a prisoner entitled to a discharge (1813 May 1); gun powder stored in the magazine (1813 June 10, 1814 June 22, & 1814 Dec. 3); the conduct of William Haw (1813 June 12); a plot to blow up the Penitentiary with gun powder from the Magazine (1813 July 21); a contract to supply the Penitentiary with coal & wood (1813 Aug. 4); and the amount of gun powder purchased at Fredericksburg (1814 July 29). Especially significant are the Keeper's reports on the number of prisoners received into the Penitentiary, the number discharged, the number remaining, their occupations, and articles manufactured at the Penitentiary (1812 Feb. 12; 1812 July 1; 1812 Dec. 17; & 1813 July 1).
Philip Norborne Nicholas, Attorney General, provides opinions on issuing commissions to sheriffs (1812 March 8); the sentence of Joseph Findlay (1813 May 29); the case of the Deputy Assessor for Russell County (1813 July 5); items on the account of Samuel Pleasants, Public Printer (1813 Nov. 29); and the case of James Malone & the serving of consecutive terms for several offenses (1814 May 5). He also writes on the following subjects: suits against the Commonwealth for certain fees claimed for services alleged to have been performed in escheated lands (1812 Feb. 9); witnesses against John McCall charged with robbing the Treasury (1812 March 23); his declining to go to Norfolk to attend the Superior Court (1812 July 10); the claim of James Taylor for property burnt in Norfolk (1813 Feb. 23); and the application of Richard H. Baker as notary public at Suffolk (1813 March 2).
William Munford, as Clerk of the House of Delegates, & Theodosius Hansford, Clerk of the Senate, often submit legislation to the Governor. Noteworthy, is a resolution requesting the Executive to lay before the Assembly the correspondence regarding the claim of the Commonwealth to reimburse them for various expenditures in calling out the militia since 1 January 1807 (1813 May 19); a resolution requesting the Executive lay before the House a statement of the expenses incurred in the defense of the Commonwealth (1813 Dec. 7); a resolution requesting the Executive to lay before the House a statement of the manner in which the detachment of the militia ordered out for the defense of the Commonwealth by the general orders of 6 February 1813 (1813 Dec. 13); a resolution to purchase match-coats for the use of the militia in service at Norfolk or elsewhere (1814 Fe. 15); a resolution regarding the removal of the restrictions imposed by the law upon the transportation of the arms of the Commonwealth beyond the limits thereof (1814 Oct. 12); a resolution regarding Treasury notes received by the Federal government (1814 Nov. 14); a resolution regarding the accounts of the Commonwealth adjusted with the Federal government (1814 Nov. 14); an act authorizing a loan for the pay & support of the troops in the service of the Commonwealth (1814 Nov. 18); and a resolution requesting a report of the number of militia detained for service under the requisition of 1812 (1814 Dec. 9).
Additionally, Munford transmits extracts from the House Journal regarding the elections of the following individuals: Peter V. Daniel as Privy Councilor (1812 Jan. 7); John G. Jackson as Brigadier General (1812 Jan. 9); Daniel Smith as judge of the General Court (1813 Jan. 22); Peter Randolph, Jr., as judge of the General Court (1812 Jan. 22); James Allen as judge of the General Court (1812 Jan. 22); Robert Nelson as judge of the Superior Court of Chancery for the District of Williamsburg (1812 Dec. 4); William G. Pendleton as Register of the Land Office (1814 Oct. 17); and John Burfoot as Auditor of Public Accounts (1814 Oct. 18).
Samuel Shepard, Auditor of Public Accounts, corresponds with Governor Barbour regarding various financial matters. Shepard regularly encloses accounts of expenses for forwarding notices, executions, etc. (1812 June 24; 1812 Sept. 5; 1813 March 19; 1813 May 3; 1813 Aug. 18; 1814 March 7; 1814 April 23; 1814 Aug. 22). In addition, Shepard writes concerning a list of counties where there have been no collectors of the revenue (1812 Feb. 1); a list of notaries public in office (1812 March 5); the tax on seines for the year 1811 (1812 March 7); accounts between the Penitentiary & the Commonwealth (1812 March 26; 1813 March 15; & 1814 April 13); the high sheriff on Monongalia County's levy of a fini facias on the lands of Stephen Morgan (1812 May 30); Joseph Faucett, the agent for collecting arrears of taxes from the securities of William Nall, former sheriff of Rockingham County (1812 June 16); a statement of the Keeper of the Penitentiary showing the commissions due him on profits from 1 December 1811 to 13 May 1812 (1812 July 3); accounts for postage (1812 July 6; 1812 Aug. 12; 1812 Sept. 25; 1813 April 30; 1813 July 1 & 3; 1813 Aug. 20; 1813 Oct. 7; 1814 Aug. 17, 24, & 27; 1814 Sept. 28); the appointment of an agent to attend the sale of George Rennie's land in Randolph County (1812 July 9); lists of warrants drawn on the Contingent Fund (1812 Oct. 6; 1813 April 22); the account of the U. S. with Virginia (1812 Oct. 13); the fund appropriated for distributing public arms (1812 Oct. 19); an execution against Morgan Tompkins, late sheriff of Gloucester County (1813 March 6); the appointment of an agent to superintend the sale of land in Kanawha County (1813 May 21); accounts & vouchers returned to the Auditor's Office (1813 June 18); the settlement of accounts of Paymaster Pendleton (1813 June 16); money advanced to Col. Nathaniel Cargill, Quartermaster, to the troops ordered to Norfolk (1813 Aug. 4); returns of the Commissioner of Revenue for the Borough of Norfolk (1813 Oct. 16); the lack of collectors of the revenue for Harrison, Nansemond, Norfolk, Princess Anne, & York counties (1814 Feb. 20); debt due the Commonwealth from Morgan Tompkins, late sheriff of Gloucester County (1814 Feb. 23); the amount of unexpended funds in the Military Contingent Fund (1814 July 16); executions issued against William Morris, late sheriff of Kanawha County (1814 July 18); warrants drawn on the Military Contingent Fund (1814 Aug. 23 & 1814 Sept. 23); and the account of Peyton Drew, Clerk of the General Court (1814 Sept. 6). Samuel Shepard resigned as Auditor of Public Accounts and was replaced by John Burfoot on 18 October 1814.
Governors from other states comprise a significant amount of correspondence received by the Governor. Included are letters from the following governors David B. Mitchell, Georgia; William Hawkins, North Carolina; Elbridge Gerry & Caleb Strong, Massachusetts; William Jones, Rhode Island; Joseph Bloomfield, New Jersey; William Blount, Tennessee; Roger Griswold & John Cotton Smith, Connecticut; Robert Bowie, Maryland; William Plumer, New Hampshire; Return J. Meigs, Ohio; Daniel D. Tompkins, New York; Simon Snider, Pennsylvania; W. C. C. Claiborne, Louisiana; and Daniel Rodney, Delaware.
Governor David B. Mitchell, Georgia, transmits a resolution in favor of the proposed amendment to the Constitution against any citizen accepting any title of nobility or honor from a foreign power from holding public office (1812 Jan. 4). Governor William Plumer, New Hampshire, transmits a similar resolution on 12 December 1812. Governor William Hawkins, North Carolina, transmits a proposed amendment to the Constitution regarding the election of representatives to Congress and the appointment of electors to vote for President & Vice President (1812 Jan. 4 & 1813 Jan. 4). Hawkins also transmits an act ratifying the amendment to the Constitution regarding titles of nobility (1812 Jan. 14). On several occasions, Hawkins transmits copies of the laws of North Carolina (1812 March 26; 1813 April 14; & 1814 April 13). He also writes regarding the demand for John Williams, a fugitive from justice (1812 April 9). Governor Elbridge Gerry, Massachusetts, encloses a resolution of the Massachusetts Legislature to wear a badge of mourning for the death of Governor George William Smith in the Richmond Theater fire (1812 Jan. 14). Governors William Jones, Rhode Island; Joseph Bloomfield, New Jersey; William Blount, Tennessee; & Roger Griswold, Connecticut; write to acknowledge the receipt of the resolutions of the Virginia Assembly on the right to instruct their senators in Congress (1812 March 9, 10, & 20). Governor Robert Bowie, Maryland, writes on 24 July 1812 transmitting a copy of the laws of Maryland. Governor Return J. Meigs, Ohio, transmits resolutions relative to the jurisdictional right of the state of Ohio over the Ohio River (1813 Jan. 18). Governor William Blount, Tennessee, writes on 4 July 1813 regarding the demand for a fugitive named William Crush. Governor Daniel D. Tomkins, New York, writes regarding Thomas Williams, a free negro confined in Norfolk (1813 Aug. 21). Governor John Cotton Smith, Connecticut, writes to acknowledge receipt of the acts of the Virginia Legislature (1813 Nov. 18). Governor Simon Snider, Pennsylvania, encloses a resolution of the House of Representatives for an amendment to the Constitution to reduce the term of service in Congress from six years to four years (1814 March 17). Governor W. C. C. Claiborne, Louisiana, writes regarding the failure of the requisition of troops made by Gen. Flournoy to the Executive (1814 March 30). Daniel Rodney, Delaware, transmits copies of the laws of Delaware (1814 May 10). Rodney also writes regarding a certificate of the residency of Samuel Maule in Lewes, Delaware (1814 Oct. 28). Lastly, Caleb Strong, Massachusetts, encloses the votes against an amendment to the Constitution proposed by Pennsylvania & Tennessee to reduce the terms of senators in Congress (1814 Oct. 11).
Additional significant correspondence includes the following: Edward Christian, Clerk of the Court, re. the death of Samuel Tyler, Judge of the Chancery District Court at Williamsburg (1812 March 23); James Barbour to Peyton Randolph re. an error in his circular to the commandants of regiments which failed to enumerate York County (1812 April 24); William Price & Thomas Underwood encl. an estimate for digging & walling a canal from the present canal to the Public Warehouse in Richmond (1812 April 20); John Tyler, Jr., re. the formation of a volunteer company in Charles City County (1812 May 4); William Tatham re. his report of the defense of the maritime frontier of the Commonwealth (1812 May 8, 9, & 10); William Tatham re. the defense of Lynhaven Bay (1812 May 14); William Tatham encl. a sketch of a telegraph on the lever principle designed by him to communicate from Lynhaven Bay to Richmond in twenty-five minutes (1812 May 17); William Tatham re. the survey of a military canal from Lynhaven Bay to the eastern branch of the Elizabeth River (1812 May 20); James Greenhow re. the sick and a hospital at the Penitentiary (1812 May 28); John Preston, Treasurer, requesting to remove his office to one of the unoccupied rooms in the upper part of the Capitol during the summer months (1812 July 18 & 1813 May 31); Lt. Gov. Charles K. Mallory re. his meeting with the President on behalf of the Governor's applications to the Secretary of War for the defense of Norfolk (1812 July 22); Abraham Trigg re. his appointment as one of the commissioners to run a line between the lands reserved by the Commonwealth for the benefit of the officers & soldiers of the Virginia Line between the Scioto & Miami Rivers in Ohio and the other lands ceded to the U. S. (1812 Aug. 8); Lt. Col. John Connell encl. confirmation that Forts Mackinaw, Detroit, & Mawmie are in possession of the British (1812 Aug. 27); Peter Hagner, War Dept., Accountant's Office, transmitting ten thousand dollars on account of the militia per the act of 10 April 1812 (1812 Sept. 7); Thomas T. Tucker, U. S. Treasurer, encl. a draft for ten thousand dollars issued by the Secretary of War (1812 Sept. 8); Robert Brent, Paymaster of the U. S. Army, re. the pay of officers under the command of Edward Lucas in Norfolk (1812 Sept. 25); George Williamson, Armory, encl. a list of gun powder belonging to the state of Virginia now in the Magazine (1812 Nov. 23); W. Croghan, on behalf of George Rogers Clark, re. receipt of the Governor's letter approving of his conduct as an office during the Revolutionary War & a sword voted to him by the Assembly (1812 Dec. 15); William Tatham re. a bill to amend the bill passed on 10 December 1791 authorizing him to raise a sum of money to enable him to complete his geographical work (1812 Dec. 27); William Tatham offering his services for fortifying any point or position suitable for defending against any maritime enemy (1812 Dec. 27); William Tatham requesting various documents he transmitted related to the defense of the maritime frontier, etc. (1812 Dec. 27); John Brockenbrough recommending Messrs. Douglas & Huddleston engaged in the stone work of Monumental Church to engrave the description on the pedestal of Washington's statue (1813 Jan. 5); Abraham Trigg encl. his report as one of the commissioners for running the line between the Scioto & Little Miami Rivers in the state of Ohio (includes plat) (1813 Jan. 13); James Barbour to Lt. Gov. Mallory re. an affair between the enemy and the militia of Princess Anne County (1813 Feb. 11); Thomas Wilson, Mayor of Richmond, re. a conspiracy between the slaves & free negroes to burn the city and murder the white inhabitants (1813 Feb. 12); Lt. Gov. Charles K. Mallory re. the defeat of Gen. Winchester's Northwest Army (1813 Feb. 11); Lt. Gov. Charles K. Mallory re. the passage of the Eastern Defense Bill to raise one regiment of infantry, a troop of cavalry, a company of riflemen, & two companies of artillery (1813 Feb. 13); James Wood re. the British blockade and the defenseless situation in Norfolk (1813 Feb. 13); William Crawford re. the final settlement of the yearly Penitentiary accounts by the Auditor (1813 March 3); William Armistead re. the death of Judge William Nelson (1813 March 8); Brig. Inspector James Maurice encl. a statement of Matthias Rich re. intelligence he gathered as a prisoner on board the British fleet (1813 March 8); James Maurice re. enemy movements near Hampton Roads (1813 March 9); Lt. Gov. Charles K. Mallory re. additions to the enemy force (1813 March 10); James Maurice re. movements of three ships of war into the Bay (1813 March 22); Lt. Col. Miles Selden re. the defense at Fort Powhatan (1813 March 26); Robert Saunders re. his acceptance of a commission as judge of the General Court (1813 March 26); John Clarke re. the defense of the rivers from enemy ships & encl. a copy of his letters to Gov. Cabell on 2 August & 21 August 1807 (1813 March 26); Charles W. Morgan, U. S. S. Constitution, re. a sword presented him by Virginia (1813 March 27); William Daniel re. his appointment as judge of the Williamsburg Circuit of the General Court (1813 April 3); Richard E. Parker re. the death of his grandfather Judge Richard Parker (1813 April 5); Robert Nelson re. an estimate for repairing the Capitol in Williamsburg (1813 April 7); Ellison Currie accepting his appointment as judge of the General Court to replace Richard Parker (1813 April 12); Stapleton Crutchfield re. a vast increase of the enemy & their threatening position near Hampton Roads (1813 June 21); Stapleton Crutchfield re. his retreat from Hampton with the force under his command & his confrontation with the enemy near Hampton (1813 June 25); Robert G. Scott re. the particulars of the enemy's attack on Hampton (1813 June 25); Thomas Griffin & Robert Lively re. their meeting with Admiral Warren re. hospital supplies from Norfolk, prisoners, & desolation by the enemy in Hampton (1813 July 4); Thomas Jefferson requesting an appointment for John Strode in the Commissary, Quartermaster Department, Foundry, Armory, or Penitentiary (1813 July 13); Robert Lyman re. an expected insurrection in Halifax County and encl. a clipping from The Courier (1813 July 16); Lt. Col. James McDowell re. the movements of his detachment since leaving camp at Richmond, the movements of the enemy fleet on the Potomac River, & encl. the organization of a regiment for the defense of the Potomac (1813 July 25); the Committee of Vigilance of Petersburg encl. a letter from Richard Bate re. an estimate of additional works & repairs for Fort Powhatan (1813 July 26); John G. Baxter re. his plan for destroying the British fleet by combining a gun boat & steam boat with a wheel at the bow containing a large number of cannon (1813 Aug. 1); William Mathers re. his plan to burn the enemy ships using a rifle gun firing a rocket of his own design (1813 Aug. 4); Michael Garber encl. a plan of a spherical shell to fire at the British ships (1813 Aug. 10); James Greenhow suggesting the removal of the British prisoners in the Penitentiary (1813 Aug. 13); Christopher Ford re. his invention to convey torpedoes (1813 Sept. 7 & 10); Robert Greenhow, Mayor of Richmond, re. apprehensions of insurrection among the blacks under the instigation of the British & advising the removal of the Powder Magazine (1813 Sept. 8); Lt. Gov. Charles K. Mallory to Robert B. Taylor re. pay & rations for militia in actual service of the U. S. (1813 Oct. 1); John Turberville to William Hening encl. a letter from him to the Commander of the British Naval Forces in the Potomac re. escaped slaves on board British vessels & a letter from Capt. William Middleton re. his trip to the British ship Dragon to see the slaves on board (1813 Nov. 8); James McDowell encl. a letter from Robert B. Taylor re. four British prisoners at Richmond (1813 Dec. 7); Arthur Sinclair, U. S. Navy, re. the resolution of the General Assembly commending his services on the late contests on Lake Ontario (1814 Jan. 16); William Simmons re. accounts for expenditures made for militia services (1814 March 8); Governor Barbour to the Secretary of War re. the retirement of Gen. Thomas Parker from command at Norfolk & his order for Brig. Gen. Chamberlayne to take command (1814 March 20); Brig. Gen. William Chamberlayne re. the refusal of Col. Freeman to transfer command of the troops in Norfolk to any state office unless directed by the War Dept. (1814 March 31); H. S. G. Tucker re. intelligence that the enemy are in possession of the Westmoreland Courthouse (1814 July 25); John Davenport re. the death of Charles Blagrove, Register of the Land Office (1814 Aug. 20); William W. Hening, Clerk of the Superior Court of Chancery for the Richmond District, re. the removal of court papers in cases of invasion or insurrection (1814 Aug. 26); William C. Williams re. the position of the enemy fleet at the mouth of Occoquan Creek (1814 Aug. 28); William C. Williams re. the action against the enemy near Blandensburg, Maryland, & the burning of the Navy Yard, Capitol, & War Office in Washington (1814 Aug. 28); William C. Williams re. the removal of the enemy from Washington, the damage to the Capitol & President's house, & the location of the Secretary of War (1814 Aug. 28); Walter G. Anderson, U. S. Navy, offering his services in sinking old vessels in the James River to stop the enemy fleet (1814 Sept. 7); John Davenport re. his safe arrival at Cartersville with the records & papers of the Land Office (1814 Sept. 11); Lt. Col. Archibald Ritchie re. the possession of the enemy of the town of Essex (1814 Dec. 1); and Governor Barbour to the Council thanking them for their kindness & support during his time in office (1814 Dec. 10).
Other noteworthy items include: certificate of oaths for Nathaniel H. Claiborne, James Wood, & Peter V. Daniel as members of the Privy Council (1812 Jan. 8 & 9); a certificate of oath for John Russell as Clerk of the Council (1812 Jan. 15); the bond of John Staples as Superintendent of the Manufactory of Arms (1812 Feb. 18); proceedings of the Monthly Board of Visitors at the Penitentiary (1812 Feb. 19; 1812 Sept. 7; 1813 July 10; 1813 Oct. 16); proceedings of the Quarterly Meeting if the Board of Visitors (1812 July 8; 1812 Oct. 19; 1812 Dec. 15; 1813 May 24; 1813 Sept. 7; 1813 Nov. 22; 1814 April 8; 1814 July 11); a proclamation by Lt. Gov. Charles K. Mallory offering a reward for the apprehension of William Crush (1812 March 2); a proclamation by Lt. Gov. Charles K. Mallory appointing James Johns as agent to convey David Bosworth, a fugitive from justice in Maryland, to the jail of Prince Edward County (1812 March 9); a report by the Governor to the Council re. his visit to the eastern frontier for the purpose of collecting information on the defense of the state against invasion (1812 May 12); certificates of oath for Robert Quarles & John Campbell as a members of the Privy Council (1812 May 28 & 1812 June 1); a report of the committee appointed to make certain enquiries of the Superintendent of the Armory (1812 Aug. 15); appointments of electors for President & Vice President (1812 Aug. & Sept.); a report of the commissioners to explore the upper navigation of the James River (1812 Oct. 26); a certificate of the services of Robert H. Harrison by Bushrod Washington (1812 Nov. 24); a certificate of Robert Taylor, Speaker of the Senate, & Andrew Stevenson, Speaker of the House of Delegates, re. the election of electors to supply vacancies (1812 Dec. 2); a proclamation by Governor Barbour offering a reward for the apprehension of Peter Pippets (1812 Dec. 8); a proclamation by Governor Barbour offering a reward for the apprehension of Daniel Beach (1812 Dec. 9); a proclamation by Governor Barbour offering a reward for the apprehension of Malichie Branham (1813 Jan. 23); a resolution of William B. Lamb, Mayor, & George Newton, President of the Common Council, that Richard E. Lee & Robert B. Taylor be appointed to proceed to Richmond & Washington to represent the state & federal government on the exposed & defenseless situation at Norfolk (1813 Feb. 1); appointments of officers in the corps to be raised for the defense of the state (1813 March); a report by Samuel Shepard on the Penitentiary accounts (1813 March 15); a proclamation by Governor Barbour offering a reward for the apprehension of John Emery (1813 April 1); a report of the commissioners appointed to lay off the city of Richmond into wards (1813 April 2); a proclamation by Governor Barbour offering a reward for the apprehension of Benjamin Miller (1813 April 10); an act of Congress to encourage vaccination by appointing James Smith a vaccine agent in Baltimore and to transfer vaccine matter free of postage (1813 May 4); advice of the Council re. the letter of Lt. Col. James Robinson, Princess Anne County, informing the Governor of the enemy's landing, depredations, & repulsion by a detachment of militia (1813 June 21); pay roll of Capt. James Bonner's Company of drafted militia detached from the 63rd Regiment stationed at Fort Powhatan (1813 July 12); pay roll of Capt. Thomas E. Fortune's Company of Artillery detached from the 2nd Regiment stationed at Fort Powhatan (1813 July 26); an inventory of stores belonging to the Commonwealth on board the Schooner First Attempt (1813 Sept. 6); a certificate of oath for Arthur Smith as a member of the Privy Council (1813 Dec. 27); the bond of Charles Blagrove as Register of the Land Office (1814 Jan. 6); a proclamation by Governor Barbour offering a reward for the apprehension of the slaves Cyrus Archer, Field Archer, & Dick (1814 Jan. 17); proceedings of the Richmond Committee of Vigilance (1814 Feb. 3); a proclamation by Lt. Gov. Linah Mims directing that the county & superior courts for Campbell County be held in Lynchburg (1814 March 11); a proclamation by Governor Barbour directing that the county & superior courts for York County be held at the house of Matthew Wells in the town of York (1814 March 16); a proclamation by Governor Barbour re. an election to replace John Dawson as a representative of Congress (1814 April 14); a bill of repairs on the Capitol by Richard Garret (1814 April 26); a proclamation by Governor Barbour offering a reward for the apprehension of John Robertson (1814 April 27); a presentment by the Richmond Hustings Court re. the removal of the Powder Magazine away from the Penitentiary to a more suitable distance away from the city (1814 May 12); extracts of the general orders of Brig. Gen. Robert B. Taylor and the surgeons of the army at Norfolk re. the appointment of Dr. J. T. Barraud as Surgeon General (1813 June 5); a survey of land belonging to the Commonwealth at Westham in Henrico County (1814 July 9); the bond of Robert Hyde to erect a building for the deposit of munitions of war (1814 July 28); proceedings of the Mayor & Aldermen of Richmond re. the city's present state of defenses (1814 Aug. 20); a proclamation by Governor Barbour calling the General Assembly into session on the 2nd Monday of October (1814 Sept. 1); a report of a survey of the road from Camp Fairfield to New Bridge on the Chickahominy River down to Bottom Bridge with a list of houses on the main direct road from Richmond to the Brick House, etc. (1814 Sept. 17); a report of the President & Directors of the Literary Fund (1814 Oct. 1); a resolution of the Vermont Legislature against the amendments proposed by the Legislatures of Tennessee & Pennsylvania to reduce the term of service for senators in Congress (1814 Nov. 4); and a proclamation by Governor Barbour offering a reward for the apprehension of Larkin Cottrell (1814 Nov. 26).